Guide to the John C. Mersick Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
John C. Mersick family papers
1856-1903
MS 1425
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.25
(1 box)
The papers consist of correspondence, writings, and notes of John C. Mersick and his son Charles S. Mersick, both merchants in nineteenth-century New Haven, Connecticut. John C. Mersick's papers relate to his historical interests and the Washington Union Brotherhood. The papers also document Charles S. Mersick's genealogical interests.
Mersick, John C., 1804-1887
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Whitlock's in 1945. The papers were originally part of the Miscellaneous Manuscripts Collection, MS 352.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The John C. Mersick Family Papers consist of correspondence, writings, and notes of John C. Mersick (1804-1887) and his son Charles S. Mersick (1840-1904). Both men were nineteenth century merchants in New Haven. The papers of John C. Mersick relate to his historical interests and include speeches given by him as assistant historian of the Washington Union Brotherhood, a social and charitable fraternity which Mersick helped to found, ca. 1861. Charles S. Mersick's papers include a few letters to his father and notes and correspondence which relate to his genealogical interests.
The Yale Library purchased the papers from Whitlock's in 1945. They were transferred from the Miscellaneous Manuscripts Collection in 1985.
Genealogy; New Haven (Conn.); Businessmen; Mersick, Charles S., 1840-; Mersick, John C., 1804-1887; Mersick family; Washington Union Brotherhood (New Haven, Conn.)
- Inventory
  - Mersick, John C.
    - Memorandum book containing a chronology of world history, Circa 1885 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Papers re: Washington Union Brotherhood, 1877, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Mersick, Charles S.
    - Letters to John C. Mersick, 1856, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - General
    - Genealogical correspondence, 1894-1900 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Genealogical notes, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Miscellanea, 1861, 1903, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)